<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
         xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
         xmlns:gi2mo="http://purl.org/gi2mo/ns#"
         xmlns:inov="http://purl.org/innovonto/types/#">

    <gi2mo:IdeaContest rdf:about="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/ideaContests/i2m-TCO">
        <inov:hasChallenge rdf:resource="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/challenges/i2m-TCO"/>
        <dcterms:title>Transparent Conductive Oxides (TCO)</dcterms:title>
        <dcterms:description>In the first test phase of the project, "Transparent Conductive Oxides" (TCO) was selected
            as the technology, which was developed by the Leibniz Institute for New Materials (INM). TCO are conductive
            and flexible materials which are used in the form of thin coatings in various areas (e.g. foils or
            displays).
        </dcterms:description>
        <dcterms:created>2017-09-21</dcterms:created>
        <gi2mo:startDate>2018-03-09</gi2mo:startDate>
        <gi2mo:endDate>2018-09-24</gi2mo:endDate>

        <rdfs:seeAlso
                rdf:resource="https://i2m.imp.fu-berlin.de/ergebnisse/"/>

        <rdfs:comment>
            Explorer-Phase: 14.05.2018 - 27.05.2018
            Elaborator-Phase: 04.06.2018 - 10.06.2018
            Group Workshop: 20.06.2018
        </rdfs:comment>

    </gi2mo:IdeaContest>

    <inov:Challenge rdf:about="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/challenges/i2m-TCO">
        <dcterms:title>Transparent Conductive Oxides: Ideas to Market Challenge Number 1</dcterms:title>
        <gi2mo:hasIdeaContest rdf:resource="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/ideaContests/i2m-TCO"/>
        <inov:hasResearchDescription rdf:resource="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/researchDescriptions/i2m-tco-detailed"/>
    </inov:Challenge>

    <inov:ResearchDescription rdf:about="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/researchDescriptions/i2m-tco-detailed">
        <gi2mo:hasIdeaContest rdf:resource="https://innovonto-core.imp.fu-berlin.de/entities/ideaContests/i2m-TCO"/>

        <dcterms:title>Detailed Research Description</dcterms:title>
        <dcterms:created>2018-03-09</dcterms:created>
        <!-- TODO How to include the images? -->
        <dcterms:description>
            What is TCO?
            Transparent conductive oxides are materials that can be used as thin coatings to make materials and surfaces
            intelligent. They are transparent, conductive and flexible.

            What is the function?

            TCO coatings transform surfaces from objects and rooms into conductive and therefore interactive and
            touch-sensitive surfaces. Due to its transparency the original look and texture of surfaces is not changed.

            How can it be used?

            With TCO ink widely differing materials and objects can get coated, such as:
            - Temperature-sensitive materials such as plastic foils
            - Three-dimensional molded geometries
            - Complex geometries
            - Small and thin objects
            - large surfaces
            - flexible materials

            Where is it already used?

            TCO coatings have versatile use cases such as smart labels, smart watches, intelligent textiles and
            instruments. For manufacturing, TCO ink is spread out over large areas of plastic foil, paper, glass or
            textiles, resulting in extremely thin and transparent electronic components.

            Transparent conductive oxides are used to manufacture displays and touch screens. With TCO ink transparent
            electrodes are printed on to plastic foil. The flexibility allows for use in flexible displays and touch
            screens.

            TCO can be used as coatings for electrochromic devices such as Smart Windows, sun roofs, rearview mirrors,
            temperature-regulating windows in buildings or UV protection

            How is it made?

            In the process of making TCO coatings and patterns, TCO ink is used. The TCO ink is made out of
            Indium-Tin-Oxide (ITO) nanoparticles with an average size of 30 nanometers. ITO particles are dispersed in a
            solvent by using a surfactant. The dispersion is mixed with a binder and a photo initiator before printing.
            The ink can be applied as coatings or patterns by so called wet chemical methods, as e.g. printing,
            dip-coating and spray coating in a single step. Afterwards the printed films are hardened under
            UV-irradiation at low temperatures under 130°C.

            With roll-to-roll production (R2R), plastic and metal foils can be imprinted in a fast and cost-efficient
            way. It starts with a roll of a flexible material that is re-reeled after the process to create an output
            roll. The R2R-process is cost-efficient with low material consumption and can use conventional printing
            processes like gravure and Inkjet printing with low temperature.

            What are the advantages for manufacutring?

            In contrast to conventional manufactruring processes (e.g. sputter) of TCO coatings, the coating with TCO
            ink can be made in one single process step. Such production times and manufacturing costs can be reduced.
        </dcterms:description>
    </inov:ResearchDescription>
</rdf:RDF>